Jai Hind.  Brother, nowadays everyone is doing SIP.  He is
investing money in mutual funds
and that is a very good thing.  Everyone wants that
brother, inflation should be beaten and brother, those who are
providing knowledge etc. on this.
Many thanks to him.  Now that is why there
is a company called ICICI, among all ICICI,
Prudential AMC whose IPO is coming.  There
is also a shareholder quota.  Who will get it and who will
not?  Should I apply for IPO
or not?
Hi everyone my name is Bhor Vashane.  I am a
SEBI registered research analyst.
Till date, three or four IPOs of HDFC company have come
and all of them have opened in the listing gas.
Four IPOs of ICICI have come and all
three have opened in loss.  Will
ICI be able to break the jinx this time?  Will not be able to
break it.  How do I apply for a pool?
Two applications will be required on the same PAN card.
Shareholder quota will be available or not.  Has
this sector produced returns
or not?  Without wasting
time let's deep drive into our analysis.
But yes before moving ahead.  If you have
not yet subscribed to the channel or are a new
user, you will find all of them here.
IPO comparison was done of Corona and
Meesho Strong Rose Park Made, you can check this
brother.  The IPO is closing tomorrow.
Then after that the Vegfit keys bounced dot to dot from there.
Look IC, first let me
show you the IPO table.  These two IPOs have been
closed here.  These two IPOs are going to close tomorrow.
Today we are analyzing
ICICI Pro AMC.  Then after that it will be the turn of
KSH International, whatever company it is, we will see
about it.  Now look what is the first thing?
They ask who are our peer comparisons
?  ICI Pro AMC, HDFC, Nipon,
UTI, Aitya Birla.  However, I was wondering
why they did not buy Canara Robeco,
that too an AMC which had just come out for IPO.
First it is important to check whether this
sector will stand with me for the next 2 years, 4 years, 5
years, like CDSL, it is BS,
right, but the stocks in the capital market have
made money.  Let's do something.  Let's
check it quickly.  Let's
talk about HDFC AMC.  Look,
after 2020, a rally has already come.  Right?   It is
important to understand what happened after the rally that took place after Covid.  Meaning,
even after the wave went away, if we see
in 2023, it was trading somewhere around ₹800,
from ₹800 it went nonstop to ₹2400.
That means this is a 3x rally.  After that there was a
pullback to 1800.  Then from 1800 it
went up to 3000 now.  I have completed the journey from 800 to 3000.  It has happened almost
4x in the
last 2 years.  So one thing
is clear that it has created a good amount of growth.
Ok?  Let's see on the next one.
Nipon Let's
talk about Nipon.  Same
chart structure is there here also.  How much does one make in 2023
?  Around ₹200.  From 200 to
nonstop 825 that happened 3x.  This has become 4x.
A pullback came from back, same as HDFC and
went back up.  Almost reached 1000 by
making 425x in the last two years.  All these
charts we are seeing are weekly
charts.  Ok?  Let's move on to the next one.  The
structure of Next One is UTI
AMC.  Now in UTI AMC also, a
low was formed here in 2023.  Butt butt where was it trading
?  Around ₹600.  From ₹600 it went down to ₹100.
So that means it is almost 2x.  One is 3x, one is
4x, one is 2x.  There was a pullback.   If I
look at the current situation, it has been around 600 to 1120.  Even if I
assume it to be nearly double,
40% CAGR has been given for 2 years
also.  Right?  That means it has
also produced returns.  It has been
made at a slow speed in comparison to others.  Let's go
to the fourth one.  So here comes
Aditya Birla.  Here too, the low was imposed in 2023 itself.
But now let's look at one thing about it.  If
I look from 2023, the low here was
around ₹300.  Went from ₹300 to ₹900.
Current is also up to 700.  But if I
look here when it was listed, it is
trading at the same place where it was listed.
So it did not generate any returns for the last 4 years.  The
bottom of all these was formed in 2023. What are AMCs?
Brother, when you invest money in mutual funds
through SIP, lumpsum etc., there is
a fund manager sitting there. This
company will have many schemes etc., there will be
ETFs on gold,
on silver etc. or it will be direct,
hybrid etc. So what
happens there is that they charge small commissions like 1%, 75%
etc. saying that we are
sitting in your place, we will manage your money etc., we will
give you units etc., that is called
AMC.
Now let us talk about Canara RBCO.
Recently its IPO came, its IPO was priced at Rs 266.
Right?  From here let's see it
opened around 266 to 280.  Went nonstop till 350.   There was a
gradual pullback.  Currenty
is 266 to 281.  How much has happened now though?   It took
around 2 and a half months.  There is not much data but still there are
10 to 15% returns.
In 2 1/2 months.  It's well and good.  It's not that it's
bad.  Saw the charts of all five.   It is
good for the long term.  On an
average it has produced good returns.
Talking about AMC Aditya Birla, it did
not give much returns.  But yes, HDFC Nipon
UTI has given it.  So one thing
is clear that if someone wants to keep it for 2 years or 5 years down the
line, he can do so.  Now let's
start the story of ICICI AMC i.e. Prove
AMC.  Then after that I will go and
explain who will get the share holder or not.  I am going to make a detailed video.
Come brother, where has the business model gone?  Firstly, the
change that he has made, the way he has
changed himself, has he changed or has he
changed?  It was great poetry.  Incorporated in
1993, ICI Prudential AMC is an asset management
company.  Its investment approach has always been
to manage risk first and aim
for long term returns for their customers.
Every AMC has the same thing.  What is the
average asset under management (AUM) as of quarterly
?  To A 10146
billion, oh my god, this is the
average as per the quarter, QA is written, the company
offers portfolio management services, well
AIF etc., advisory services,
right PMS where someone manages your proper
account, AIF is written in which
you can also invest in unlisted.  The company
manages the largest number of schemes in the
mutual fund industry.  In September, it is
said that there are 143 schemes in which equity has
come, equity oriented has come, debt
schemes have come, passive schemes, domestic
funds and funds have come.  Liquid Scheme,
Overnight Scheme, Arbitrage and so on.  It is
said this way.
We have 272 offices etc.  It does not matter whether there is an office or not in 23 states and four UTs
because
all the work is mostly done online etc.   There is
mutual fund, PMS, AIF and
he has written about this company.   It is
functioning like a normal mutual fund company.
Ok?  Let's come to the next part.  Let us
first look at some important dates.  Then after that I will also get some important
ratios etc. checked.   I
will also get the financials checked to see what the
financials are etc.  Talking about the timeline, the
IPO will open on the 12th.  The
IPO will close on the 16th.
Allotment will come on 17th.  Refunds and
shares are going to be listed on the 18th and 19th.
Now come to the price band and
be ready for a big shock.   The
price band says ₹1 face value.  The
price band is 2165.  At a price band of ₹10,
this would be around ₹21650.
We have kept a lot of six shares
and the entire lot
is OFS.  Offer is for sale.  Mostly
OFS will come in this type of companies like Can Obco.  Don't expect to be
charged more for this type of transaction.  Because
money is already being taken from investors etc.
When you invest in mutual funds
etc., they say there
is an IPO of Rs 10,600 crore.  The entire thing is OFS.  There
is no problem.  There is no major part
for this type of companies.
We checked this also.  Now let us come to
Kota.  QIBs are said to get 50%.
Retailers have 35.  HAI
is 15%.  Number one.  I come to number two.  Now
comes the story of shareholder quota.  A
retailer can invest a maximum of Rs 2 lakh.
Small HAIs range from 2 to 10.
Big HNI has grown from 10 onwards.
Shareholder quota is also similar to retail.
You can invest a maximum of Rs 10 lakh.  Now let's go further.
Brother, ICICI
Bank should have one share in this company.  I had
already made a video of this here.  I
also made a video on Timely.  Apart from that,
I also got updates done on Twitter and Telegram.
See, this is the video
where you could have bought one share of ICICI.
Now what do they think next?
Look, there is one lot worth ₹12,990.
If you go into the retail category,
what have we seen till date?  Maximum 13,
in some cases 14.  Here it says 15.  So
they already
increased the retail quota by adjusting the price in this manner.
This should be called retail quota in terms of number of lots.  The
number of shares has been increased.
Now let us see who will get it and
who will not.  Let us understand first.
When did I even put it here?  It is about
28th, brother, you have to buy one share
for retail.  I want to buy one share of ICICI Bank.
Say one bye, say two byes, it does
n't matter.  Futures and options will
not be available.  This doubt comes in the mind of many people.
I have invested money in such a mutual fund
or in the mutual fund of ICI AMC itself.
So will shoulder quota be
available?  Will not get it.  Friend, mutual funds
and ETFs etc. do not count.
What does the Count do?  Plum Equity
Shares.   Let's
come to the next one.  Now ICI has filed DRHP.
Have already informed this.  Those who bought
ICICI Bank till 4th December.
Even if it is taken on the 4th, it will still be counted.   There
is no problem.  The name will appear on the record date.  Votes
taken on or before December 4 will be
counted.  If it is taken after that, then 5 6 7
8 is not going to be counted.  Right brother, it's time
for the video which I am making today.
Now let me explain how this is going to work.
What can you put as number one?  They
quickly see what all they can't apply.
Number one, you can either apply for maximum share holder
quota that brother, I can
apply for 15 lots in share holder quota
if you had ICICI Bank shares before 4th December.
Number one, number two or
you can invest in retail and you can
also invest 15 lots in share holder quota.
In this also you can mix 15 lots, one lot, two lots, five
lots, six lots, anything.   The
third option is that I should invest in HAI category plus
share holder quota.  The fourth option
I have is to invest only in retail.  The
fifth option is that I should invest in HAI.
This option is for those who had ICICI
Bank, they will be able to apply for shareholder quota.
If you did not have it then you
can invest it in retail or HAI.  Sixth Option Can
I
invest in Retail Plus HAI Plus Shareholder Quota
?  The answer is no.  You can
combine only one category with shareholder quota.
Ither Retail and HAI.  This is the crux.
What will happen first?  You will invest in retail.   The
mandate will be sent to the UPI ID.  You will approve.
You will go back after some time.
Now you will switch the category to retail or
you will select share holder quota.   If you are an
employee then you are an employee.  Then after that the
mandate will again go to the same UP ID and you
can apply.  So what happened with this method
?
I applied for two applications using the same PAN card.  There are chances of increasing an allotment
which we saw in HDB.
Saw it in Bajaj Housing etc.
Saw it in NTPC.  This is that method.
Still, if you have any doubt related to this, then feel free to
ask in the comment section.  Let's come back.
Now we will come to the financials.
Financials are left because it is a
complete OFS, so there is no major part in it.
Here is the date for September.
This is not useful for me.  I'm not going to do a Q on Y O
Y comparison.  Let's
move ahead completely.   There were
assets worth Rs 2800 crore.  It became 3500, then 43
and in six months it became 48.  The
growth of many assets is good.  Talking about income, the
income was Rs 2800 crore in which there is a
profit of Rs 1500 crore.  I was telling the same thing about
Cra RBCO also because
they have very good margins.  Income reached Rs 3700 crore
and profit reached around Rs 2000 crore.   It
directly became 49 and it became around Rs 2600 crore.
How much have they got now?  2900
crores.  The income was Rs 3000 crore and the
profit was Rs 1600 crore.  Just look at what you used to
earn in a year.  Now he is earning in
two quarters in 6 months.  Same goes
for profit.  They used to make a profit of Rs 1500 crore
in the entire year.  They say now yes
in two quarters.  They withdraw Rs 1600 crore in just six months.  There is
no need for borrowings etc. because the reserves are full and
brother is sitting comfortably on the pile of cash.   Let's
talk about Kent ratios.  Return on
equity 82 is very good.  Return on
Net Worth 82 is very good.  EBITDA margin
is very low.  Price to
book value of 0.36 is 30% to high.
I will also show the comparison now.  Let's talk about EPS.
Is 53.  Later it will become 65.  We take this number.  The
PE ratio will later become 33.
What happened?  EPS is increasing.  PE
ratio is dropping.  PE ratio should be
high.  Then after that the promoter holding will
become 90%.  You will have to dilute it further later.
Now let us understand.  He says, our
EPS is 53.  HDFC is at 57, Nipon is at 20,
UTI is at 57 and Aitya Birla is at 32.
So the EPS is a little high
compared to HDFC and UTI.  Next, let's
take the PE ratio.  Next was the
PE ratio, it says ours was 40,
theirs was 45, 41, 19, 22, so UTI and Aditya are
trading at a little lower price.  HDFC Nipon
and ICI, all three are trading at slightly higher prices.  The
returns and net worth are good,
around 82, but let's see where the problem is.
Their price to book value was 30 13
less than half 12 two and a half times less.  UTI is 10 times
lower on the contrary and Aditya Birla is at a
price to book value of 30 per 5, just by looking at it it seems that you have brought it at a
very high price to book value.
Now let us come
to the final verdict etc., what is its final verdict
?  Let's go.
Number one, number two, number three.  Over
subscription listing in long term.   Can be
applied for long term.
Like we saw other IPOs etc.  Let me
show
you once again.  Let's talk about HDFC.  There
was a significant growth.  Currently it is trading at ₹2600 from ₹800.  Let's
talk about Nipon.  It was
somewhere for ₹250.  Trading at ₹800.  You are
looking at the margins, they are
trading on good margins, 40-50% margins.  Let's
talk about UTI.  There
was not much growth in comparison but growth has been created.
Same goes for Aitya B Birla.  There was no growth in 4 years but
after 2023 there was a rally
and now a double top has formed here around ₹900 at ₹915.  I had just
arrived at Ken Robe's, so I can't compare it much.
Although it is around its IPO price.
Now it can be applied for long term.
Now let's come to the shareholder quota
listing in and all that.  Look, if you
are a safe trader then there is
no benefit in applying in full force from multiple and
I should also apply in retail.  I
also invest in HAI or I
can also invest in share holder quota.  No,
if you are a safe trader then pick any one
category, pick retail or share
holder quota.  The shareholder quota,
however, is only around 5%.  Number two,
if you are a moderate to risky trader then
invest one or two lots.  Listen carefully.  Invest one or two lots
in the retail category.  Invest one or two lots
in the share holder quota category.  It does
n't seem like the type of person to invest money in full force.
Why?  Listing gains here are
coming in at 5 to 10% at a price to book value of 30.
This is the biggest thing that is visible that even
if you have brought it at high valuations, if we
talk about the comparison to PE ratio, if we
talk about the price to book value, then
it seems to be a little higher than the
face value of one.  Hence, all the three stocks of Mostant ICI have
not made any listing gains so far.  When those IPOs came, brother, all three of them incurred
losses.
Expect a listing gain of 5 to 10%.   The
oversubscription is already Rs 10,000 crore
IPO.  However, the anchor book looks good,
so there is going to be an oversubscription of 3 to 5X.  I'll
touch right up.
Be it a safe trader, retail or share
holder quota category, grab one or the other.   If your
risk is moderate then you can invest one or two lots in retail also.
Share holder quota: If you had
bought ICICI Bank shares before 4th December, then you
can invest there too, brother, for
long term purposes, we have already seen that you can
keep it for 2 years, 3 years, 5 years
because the PAT margin here is very good,
otherwise like every time, I will definitely
update on Twitter and Telegram that
brother, what IPO got listed on Twitter Telegram,
SME IPO is done, it is absolutely free,
you will get the community link of Twitter Telegram
in the description pin comment,
you can also join us by going there,
friends, this was ICICI proof, detailed
trade analysis of AMC, how to get share holder quota,
compare and tell us, still if you have any
doubt, we still have four days for the IPO to
close, if you have any doubt, you
can freely ask in the comment section, if you liked the video related to share holder
quota or anything else,
then
share it with friends in two-four WhatsApp groups, it will be of great
help to me, thank you
for watching the video, lots of love